<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>The blog of Swapneel</title>
 <link href="http://example.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://example.com"/>
 <updated>2016-04-04T20:05:55+05:30</updated>
 <id>http://example.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Swapneel</name>
   <email>swapneel@brainattic.in</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Python & Django Workshop at Gogte Institute of Technology and Engineering</title>
   <link href="http://example.com/programming/workshop/python/django/2016/02/12/python-django-workshop-gogte-engineering-college.html"/>
   <updated>2016-02-12T14:56:09+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://example.com/programming/workshop/python/django/2016/02/12/python-django-workshop-gogte-engineering-college</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I had the opportunity to conduct a workshop at Gogte Institute of Technology and Engineering in Introduction to Python and Django to students of 6th &amp;amp; 8th semester of Electronics and Communication branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The motivations of the college to conduct the workshop was primarily to introduce Python and Django to the students so that they are in a position to learn Python and build a small application which otherwise isn’t covered in the syllabus. The other &amp;amp; most important reason I was told was since students of E&amp;amp;C branch eventually attend campus recruitments wherein the majority of IT companies are primarily into web/mobile software/application development and less into embedded systems/core electronics, it becomes difficult for them compete. While the reasons appear quite obvious, it’s certainly important for me to know the motivations well in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering this, I decided to experiment with the schedule &amp;amp; had proposed for the workshop to be split into 2 hours everyday for 10 days. In hindsight, based on the overall feedback received after the workshop, it would be biased and naive for me to conclude that this method worked well. Perhaps, more such workshops with a similar format and there could be clarity on how this method fares in comparison to day long workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary objective I felt the workshop could satisfy, provided that it was broken down into few numbers of hours per day rather that 6-8 hours in a day were,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getting students to understand OOP, think in terms of software(how a software should function, features etc).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Embrace failure while learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe format is an important factor especially when teaching/conducting workshops to non-computer science students. I’ll reserve ‘One day workshop vs Few hours daily x n days Workshop’ as a future blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was able to start the workshop on 20th January and conclude on 6th February. Few days were lost due to my absence(planned), Sundays, non-availability of labs etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Majority of the students had brought laptops and this helped in continuity.  Since all except one, had Windows OS pre-installed, I had the golden opportunity to use Windows for 10 days after a very long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end, was felicitated by The Principal with a lovely memento.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I thoroughly enjoyed sharing and presenting and in due process also got to learn a few things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/s/kaukhoju6y1vn9c/IMG-20160311-WA0006.jpg?dl=0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/s/4hykhjaciwivaf8/IMG_20160224_115537.jpg?dl=0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>what-and-why-fosstr</title>
   <link href="http://example.com/fosstr/2015/06/18/what-and-why-fosstr.html"/>
   <updated>2015-06-18T19:23:54+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://example.com/fosstr/2015/06/18/what-and-why-fosstr</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I gave &lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/digen/fosstr-what-and-why&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; presentation in the last &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosstr.org&quot;&gt;fosstr&lt;/a&gt; meetup covering the journey so far, challenges we’re facing and suggestions for growing the group.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Journey to Hillhacks</title>
   <link href="http://example.com/hillhacks/travel/2015/05/30/journey-to-hillhacks.html"/>
   <updated>2015-05-30T14:56:09+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://example.com/hillhacks/travel/2015/05/30/journey-to-hillhacks</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Journey to Hillhacks involved multiple pitstops and it began with a bus ride(Kadamba Transport) from Belgaum Central Bus Stand to Margao(Goa). As I had to travel to Panaji since accomodation for the night(28th) had been booked at the Old Quarter Hostel Dorm. Unfortunately, there wasn’t a bus going directly to Panaji post 3PM. So the plan was to take the bus to Margao, get down at Banastarim Bridge which is roughly 15Kms from Panaji and then be fortunate enough to get a bus/transport/hitch-hike to Panaji.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan had to be improvised since there was an accident at Chorla Ghat causing massive road block for 30 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/content_link/6vW0E1OCTh5IhAktQs8rMqI1mCM1QvG9mSO0bSMSkTVO5ttdCzkxFA5ondKkg5nB/file?dl=1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With no way of knowing whether I’d be able to get a bus from Banastarim late in the evening, instead, I got down at Sanquelim Bus Stand, got a bus from KSRTC headed to Panaji. The bus reached Panaji Bus Stand at 9PM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walked a bit to reach Old Quarter Hostel. It’s a beautiful place to meet interesting people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/s/dk287p584k9yy66/IMG_20150529_001235.jpg?dl=0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is part of the Dorm and my bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/s/6wmpqhe4ciylz1f/IMG_20150528_212942.jpg?dl=0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Left early morning at 7:00AM on the 29th, hopped into a bus going towards Vasco, got down at Chicalim. Got a bus at the opposite road of the Goa International Airport. Flight left at 10:30AM and reached at 12:45:PM.  First thing I did at Delhi was to head to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.karimhoteldelhi.com/&quot;&gt;Karim’s&lt;/a&gt; and feast on delicious chicken curry and roti’s. The one mistake I made was to overlook the option to commute via the Metro from the Airport to somewhere nearby the Red Fort.  Instead, I took a bus which took longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next destination was to book the bus ticket from Delhi to McLeod Gunj/Dharamshala. The easiest way to do this would’ve been to book it online via &lt;a href=&quot;http://redbus.in&quot;&gt;Redbus&lt;/a&gt; but since I had time to kill and that BSNL 3G internet failed to work ( it failed to work in Goa as well o_O), it made sense to roam a bit, see the city and hopefully meet interesting people along the way. Managed to book a ticket at Majnu ka tilla which cost Rs. 1000/- which would leave at 7PM from Majnu ka Tilla.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 4:30PM, decided that I’ll venture out to buy electronic gear (GoPro accessories etc ) but did not know the specifics of where I’d be able to find it. So I decided to try my luck at Connaught Place. Thankfully, after a bit of asking around, was able to find GoPro accessories at Palika Bazaar. Made my way back to Majnu ka Tilla at 6:35PM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had Raj Kachori for dinner :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/s/7z1o0jok2he5hg4/IMG_20150529_205419.jpg?dl=0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reached McLeod Gunj at 6:30PM and made my way to Shiv Shakti Guest House after taking a taxi from the bus stand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/s/balfy5cbsoot4jw/IMG_20150530_081516.jpg?dl=0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, camping at &lt;a href=&quot;http://hillhacks.in&quot;&gt;Hillhacks&lt;/a&gt; :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/s/2sbwky8mibnztb3/IMG_20150531_091102.jpg?dl=0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only thing I felt I could have been much prepared is with regards to mobile Internet. For some reason, the BSNL 3G internet SIM I intended to use in the Dlink 3G Router failed to work. The other part I was sad about was that I missed my &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/digen&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; daily streak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Jon Krakauer, Into the Wild
I now walk into the wild&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
